Okay, so welcome back to our video
where we are going to talk about III Lombard.
Their quarterly
results have come. You can see the date here,
October 18, 2023. So let's see what is
written in the results further. Is there anything declared
like dividend, some
such declaration payment? Okay, dividend
is here. You can see
here, equity means dividend has been paid
for ₹1. That means it will be the face value.
Okay, so what is it, till when will it be available?
27 October is the record date. So
remember, this is a dividend of ₹1. And 27 October is the
record date. So let's move ahead and
see the numbers. The
numbers are in lax. And you
can see here that the results of insurance companies are
a little different. So,
we will see the total income here, that is
504,920. And before that it was
553,803. And before that it was the last.  If we
compare the September quarter's F of 49,903, then
this is a little better than this
and this is better than that and both mean that the
quarterly performance is good and
yearly performance is also good, so this means that
in income, that means an increase is
visible here, so let's see the expenses,
you will get to see the total expenses here, the
12 number
written here, you can see here
445,
445205 is one, 420, 682 is the expense and the
expenses before this are 398, 882, so let's see that
means how much profit has come,
we can see the operating profit here, 59715,
by the way, all these numbers are in lakhs and the one
before that was 3311
and that of the last September quarter was 5102, so that
means we were seeing a decline in the quarter
in the last June quarter, but
compared to that quarter, these numbers are
good because if we compare it with a smaller base, then it is
good.  When the result comes, if we
compare it yearly, then
also the numbers are looking a little good
in operating profit, so
we can find the net profit here once,
profit loss before tax, okay,
so here we have already seen the
profit loss, you can see it here at number 25, if I
want I can zoom it a little,
25, and now if we
look at it, then we can see profit loss
before tax, okay, on 27, profit loss after
tax, so here we have to see this, 57727
lakhs, this is the current profit, and the
last profit of the June quarter was 3936 lakhs,
that is, there was a profit of
3936 lakhs, and the profit of the last September quarter
was
59053 lakhs, that is, if we compare it yearly, then
we are seeing a slight decline in the numbers, slightly, and if we
compare it quarterly, then the
numbers are good, compared to the last quarter, the
numbers have come, a little
down yearly performance is visible here, so for
that  Let's go down and
see some other things. Here we are
shown EPS. Okay, earnings per share is
here, basic 11p, you can see here,
11.75, which was earlier 7.95 and before that it
was
12.03. So you can see the EPS had
reduced a lot and from there the EPS has increased a little.
So these were the results of ICICI Lord,
in which the quarterly performance was good,
that is, there was a little downgraded performance in comparison to last year,
but the
quarterly performance was good in comparison to last quarter.
We have come here. Right now the
market is live on the chart, it has reached
947 and this is the chart of ODI time
frame, you can see here
what the stock is doing today. Today the
stock closed slightly in positive, it opened
at 1.17, you can see the plus here
in the stock, so this stock is currently trading
near 1347, I will delete all this
and again we see here that it
means it is moving continuously in a channel.
And to check its long term,
we look at it on a one-month
time frame. Okay, so I've
converted it to a monthly time frame.
You can see how limited the
data is here. It started in 2018
and from there, it meant it went up a little.
Its current high is somewhere around 1700, so
its high would be somewhere around 1373. Right now, it's a
little below that high. It's trading around 1373 today. So, there's
very little data. It just
started in 2018. So, let's
look at some of the company's financial details. So,
we're here on the screener. On the
screener, we're going to look at
some of III Lord's financial data. So,
first, let's open the [ __ ] section here.
We know that they do some insurance business, so you can see it's an
insurance company. Okay, it's a leading and
established private sector general
insurance company in India. It offers a well-
diversified range of products and
risk management solutions through multiple
distribution channels. Established in  2001
JV between III Bank and Phar Flex
Financial Holding Limited. III
held 64 per stake in the company. The rest was held
by JV partner Phar Flex Financial
Asset in 2019 by selling its remaining
5 per stake in the company for 2006 crores. This
means that these two companies were formed by merging this company
and after that Phar Flex
exited from there in 2019.
They have highlighted this here. So
let's look at some numbers. Right now the
price is around 1381. The stock
is at 1.63 today because it means the results have
come out a little better as
compared to the last quarter. We can say that there are
reserves of 6784 Rs. 8 crores. This means that this is a mid
cap company and not much of a small cap company. You
can see the RE, it is 17.6, RO is 21.2,
face value is 10, book value is 230.
So you can see the stock aproxy, that is, the
approximate of its high.  5x must be trading at a
high
of 1423, which means that whatever has come in the last one year, let us
show it here.
We have already seen the chart, let us see the pros and
cons, what all is written
here, you can see in cons, it
includes order income of 988 crores, it is an
insurance company, it must be investing, so it must have received
dividend, so maybe this is
some learning related to that, insurance
companies get a lot of other income,
promoter holding has decreased
from 3.88, we have just seen that
in the last year 2019 there was an exit from
another player, so let us see,
which one is this promoter, we are going to see, the
company has reduced almost day free
and half dividend, okay, it is normal common
points, they are giving dividend,
efforts are being made to become day free,
in the insurance sector you can see the numbers here,
LIC will always be on top,
followed by ADFC Life Insurance,
followed by SBI  ICICI Prudential and now
after that, Lord works specially in ICICI Lord General Insurance.
Market, can
you see here, this market of ICICI
here is
around Rs 67848 crore, so this means the
rest of the market cap, if you see the
market cap of life insurance here,
you will see it around Rs 4 lakh and
HDFC is running at Rs 4989,
IDAC's is running at Rs 92, Live Insurance's is
running at a very low level, only Rs 8.89, which
means it is neither too high
nor too low, we
can say that the fair value is either too low or you can
understand it, and I will see the quarterly results
here, you can do it, you
can see in the open end sales, there were sales of Rs 299,
continuously increasing, then it is
in the range of Rs 4000, and now in September, there were
sales of Rs 5251, let's see the operating profit, Rs
542 crore 413, in that it showed a minus once in the last,
maybe more claims came or I do
n't know.  What might have happened? Once I
understand the insurance business well, I will
make a good, complete, proper video for you in the next four to five
days. After that, we will discuss all these things in it.
Sometimes the company keeps reporting losses here. You
can see here also that it has
reported a loss in March. Here also, it has
reported a loss in March. So
why do they report losses in March?
A separate video will come on this, it will go into details. So, don't
worry about that. 490 crores
and then 744 crores. Currently, there is a profit in the stock. So let's
see the net profit.
416, then 356, and then
ok, by the way, the loss has not been reported. Does this
mean they have incurred a loss here or is it
some kind of adjustment? In the net profit,
we can see that everything is in the green.
We can see everything in profit
continuously. So, 447,
then 300, then 591. So,
I feel that it is moving a little bit
in the same range.  There are profits etc. So this
insurance business is probably something like this. If we
look at the long term, if
we look at the age numbers of one year, then we
can see that sales were in the range of 3500-4000,
in the range of 6000, 7000-11000-12000,
17000 in March, okay, sales are increasing, that is, the
business is growing. Now let's see, the
net profit is in minus, 353-520, this is
507-700-800, okay, here we can see
continuous growth, here we are
seeing a little bit, the last
profit of March 2023 was 1729, it is in crores, by the way,
we do not have to see all the numbers, ATA,
we will see only when the date of 2024 comes, by the way, there is
no recommendation to sell or buy any kind of sale, you should
talk to your financial advisor and take a
decision accordingly or do your own research and
study yourself.  I am speaking directly
or someone else is speaking, hence one should
not buy or sell, whatever you do,
do it on your own responsibility, it is your own
money, so this was a disclaimer from my side,
after that let's go down and see
some other things related to the company, you
can see the balance sheet, we have to see here
what are the reserves and liabilities,
here you can see the borrowing
was completely zero earlier, after that it
increased a bit and now there is a long term borrowing of 35 crores,
short term borrowing also means
how much short term borrowing has not been given,
other borrowings are of 35 crores and
after that we are seeing some liabilities here in other liabilities and
if we talk about reserves, it was 1022,
from there it increased in the range of 2000,
in the range of 3000, in the range of 5000 and now that
means the latest reserves that have come are
approximate of 10800 crores, that is the
company has very good reserves.
We can say that it is maintained, let's
see the share holding pattern, let's see it briefly
so that we don't have much confusion, there are
5592 promoters, which have reduced to
48.0, there are FIs, which have increased to
22, there is a lot of confidence in it, there were
DIs at 9.16, there were mutual
funds, they have been formed, you can see the government at 18.10, there
is a share of 0.10 and the public
% has now become 11.7, so let's
see a little bit that whose names are there in the promoter holding,
in the promoter holding, only the
name of III Bank is there, III
Bank is its main parent company,
here on end 48, it was completely with II Bank,
that is, with whomever they had a
partnership, that company has already taken exit in 2019,
they have said so, so the
promoters who were there now, that is, in 2019,
maybe this is the one, see  You can see that
in 2022-21, the reduction here is
visible for the bank right now, but at one
place here, there will be some
adjustment in which that company had
sold that share, here to ICICI
Bank, so let us see which are the FADs right now, you
can see, Government of
Pension Fund, Global Government of Singapore, there are
two such Fs here,
you can see in mutual funds, there is SBI Mutual Fund, Various
Chem, Prudential
SB Mutual Fund, Motilal Oswal, Kotak,
Aditya Birla, UTI Mutual Fund,
LIC through Various Funds, Kotak and
such, Special Opportunity Fund, so there are many funds, so let us see,
in how much time, how many returns has this stock given, I have
already opened this here, the
market is currently running live, so let us
see the max returns, you will get the max returns
because the stock has just been listed, so it
means you will not get to see high returns, these are the
returns of 102 for one year, that is, since the time of
listing.  Since then the stock has
only doubled. There is a return of 69% in 5 years. There is a
return of 20% in one year. Since the
start of this sale, there is a return of 10%.
What will you do by looking at the other returns?
In one day, I mean today a hike of 1.15% is
visible here. After that we are going to see the
website of AAAAR. You can see here
what services it provides. So the
insurances that are visible here are
mostly business related insurances. You
can see here workman compensation, contractor
all risk insurance, event insurance, that is, if
something happens in a company, drone
insurance. Drones are also
mostly used for businesses. So professional
insurances that are
taken for businesses, fire insurance,
group health insurance, marine open
insurance. So here we can see such general insurance
or business insurance products
here. So let's
see some more things. I mean,
I found this website a little interesting
because they do business related things.
100% rust zero SL.  If
I ever want to start a business in the future
and I need these, then you
can see the gross return premium. It is 21.7.72 billion
rupees. The count of policies issued is 32.7
million. They have issued 3.6
million policies. The count of claims settled is 3.6 million. Here,
some codes from testing mind, different
defense things will be written here.
Strong brand and
what is there in some claim settlement innovation and area
insurance, okay, let's say fire, marine,
engineering, so they provide insurance related to these. They are
also providing drone-related insurance.
Mobile insurance also means some
thing has come here, business shield
insurance includes fire. This is a
little special here.
All the businesses here, I mean, they should
definitely check once that, I mean, if there is a
natural disaster, okay, then to
protect against it, legal liability, a whole package
like this, all the other things are here, so to
protect against any legal disaster, all these
things are very useful. Blogs Business
Insurance, okay,
these
blogs do a little work to make people aware, to give them information, or Promise Awards
Excel, okay, so here
we will look at the products, these are the things we had to
look at, Workman Compensation Group Health
Group Personal Accident, okay, Marine Ice
India, this is a scheme, then this is also a scheme,
this scheme, risk management, so there are different such
event insurance, loan insurance, collection, all these
things, so this was
insurance, that is, a
little detailed analysis about ICICI Lombard,
we will
definitely make a video in the future with even more detailed analysis, this is
not any kind of recommendation, if you
want an account where there is minimum
brokerage for investment and training, then there are
some links in the description below,
please go and check them out,
then you can open your family member's
account from there, the
account will be opened for free, for more such videos,
subscribe to our channel,
like the video, also share it with your friends,
see you in the next video,
thank you